# **Hewan Redie**

Eagan, MN. 55121

Phone: 651-621-0392 | Email: tewol22@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/hewan-redie-b5751b89 | GitHub: https://github.com/Tewol | Portfolio: https://tewol.github.io/20-react-portfolio/

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-stack developer with extensive background in various programming languages and framework. Proficient in managing all aspects of the test life cycle in software development projects from 5+ years of experience in software testing. Motivated and passionate to work independently as well as part of a team with excellent time management and problem-solving skills.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- **Programming Languages:** JavaScript, Reactjs, jQuery, Bootstrap, Nodejs, Express, Handlebars.js, HTML5, CSS, Java, Visual Basics, SQL, MIPS Assembly.
- Database: MongoDB, MySQL, Universal SQL, DB-Visualizer, SQL Server Management Studio
- Software Testing Tool: TFS/MTM, HP QC, UFT (Automation testing), JIRA bug tracking
- Version Control Tool: GitHub and TFS
- Modeling Language: UML
- Business Applications: EPIC electronic medical record system, Sunquest lab information system, PowerScribe radiology reporting platform, MSP loan servicing platform, ServiceNow, SharePoint, Microsoft Office, Avaya One-X softphone, Cisco Jabber

#### **PROJECTS**

# Bark Avenue | https://github.com/Tewol/barkAvenue | https://bark-avenue.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Pet hotel reservation website designed using Reactis.
- Role: Contributor
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Reactjs, Reactstrap, MongoDB, Heroku

# Portfolio | https://github.com/Tewol/20-react-portfolio | https://tewol.github.io/20-react-portfolio/

- Summary: Professional portfolio designed using Reactjs
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: JavaScript, Reactjs, Reactstrap, Heroku,

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **QA Analyst: Fairview Health Services**

#### Minneapolis Minnesota 02/2018 - 02/2021

- Specialized in designing and developing test plans and estimates according to technical specifications.
- Developed test cases and test scripts based on requirements and workflow documents in order to ensure proper functionality for end users.
- Executed manual and automated test scripts using different company supported platforms.
- Excelled performing functional testing, end-to-end, interface and regression testing.
- Documented and maintained defects using HP Quality Center (QC) test management tool.
- Compiled and reported daily, weekly and final test status report to project managers, application analysts and stakeholders.
- Collaborated with business analysts, application analysts, project managers and operations to ensure successful project deployment.
- Mentored and trained new team members and a size of 20+ offshore employees and provided support.
- Tasked with leading the QA testing effort of various projects because of experience and knowledge of processes and procedures with software used.
- Collaborated with a team of 13 other QA members on major or periodic releases.
- Assisted with quarterly release testing led by other QA team leads.

#### **Technical Support Analyst: Assurant**

#### Woodbury Minnesota 07/2019 - 12/2019

- Assisted and monitored batch processing on Automic, Lawson and various other platforms.
- Deployed production codes using Microsoft SQL server, Octopus, Harvest, BOM and RM.
- Run manual batch workload.
- Collaborated with 4 other team members in resolving and escalating batch related problems.
- Supported one-time/Ad Hoc batch job setup requests.

#### **QA Analyst: Ditech Financial LLC**

#### Saint Paul, Minnesota 05/2015 - 09/2017

- Analyzed and reviewed testability of business/functional requirements and design documents.
- Created test plan, test scenarios, test case and use cases for different projects.
- Performed functional testing, black-box testing, smoke, and regression testing.
- Data sourcing from multiple SQL databases to acquire test data for functional and regression testing.
- Worked closely with QA lead and business analysts to clarify requirements testability
- Partnered with developers and project managers to assess priority and severity of defects reported.
- Documented and reported software defects using bug tracking systems.
- Participated in many types of meetings such as weekly meetings, Stand up meetings, Portfolio meetings, scrum meetings, client meetings etc.
- Delivered daily and weekly status reports to the QA lead, QA manager, Project managers/directors.
- Generated test estimate, Master Test Plan, and final QA report
- Trained and coached new employees and closely worked with offshore team and provided support
- Worked with 25+ onshore and offshore QA team members on various projects and releases.

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Minnesota School of Continuing Studies, Minneapolis MN

Full Stack Flex Web Development Program

Certificate of Completion

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

#### Metropolitan State University, St. Paul MN.

Bachelor of Science Computer Science:

#### **CERTIFICATION**

ISTQB Certified Tester by American Software Testing Qualifications Board Inc.